let questions = [
    {
        id: 01,
        question: 'The planned Bedabahal Ultra Mega Power Project is in which of the following states?',
        alternatives: ['Jharkhand', 'Odisha', 'West Bengal', 'Tamil Nadu'],
        correct: 'Odisha',
        expo: 'Bedabahal is located in Sundargarh district of Odisha. There is a planned UMPP there which has so far not seen the light of the day due to various problems including those of land, coal etc.',
    },

    {
        id: 02,
        question: 'Which Indian state share the longest land border with Bhutan?',
        alternatives: ['Assam','Google', 'Arunachal Pradesh', 'West Bengal'],
        correct: 'Assam',
        expo: 'The border is 699 km long, and adjoins the Indian states of Assam (267km), Arunachal Pradesh (217km), West Bengal (183km), and Sikkim (32km).',
    },

    {
        id: 03,
        question: 'Hirakud Dam is located on which river?',
        alternatives: ['Rihand','Mahanadi','Subarnrekha','Bhargavi'],
        correct: 'Mahanadi',
        expo: 'Hirakud dam is built across the Mahanadi river, the dam is one of the World’s longest earthen dam. It is located in the state of Odisha.',
    },

    {
        id: 04,
        question: 'India’s only active volcano is located at which among the following places?',
        alternatives: ['Car Nicobar','Barren island','Maya Bunder','Lakshdweep'],
        correct: 'Barren island',
        expo: 'The Barren Island is located in the Union Territory of Andaman and Nicobar Islands and is the only confirmed active volcano in South Asia.',
    },

    {
        id: 05,
        question: 'In which among the following Petroleum in India is found chiefly?',
        alternatives: ['Basalt','Metamorphic Rocks','Sedimentary Rocks','None of the above'],
        correct: 'Sedimentary Rocks',
        expo: 'Sedimentary rocks are made from layers, or strata, of mineral particles found in other rocks that have been weathered and from newly formed organic matter.',
    },

    {
        id: 06,
        question: 'Which among the following is the largest river system among the Deccan system of rivers?',
        alternatives: ['Godavari','Cauvery','Krishna','Periyar'],
        correct: 'Godavari',
        expo: 'With a length of 1465 Kilometers, Godavari is India’s second largest river that runs within the country and also the longest river in South India.',
    },

    {
        id: 07,
        question: 'The Ganga-Brahmaputra river delta in India and Bangladesh which is one of the most fertile regions in the world is a____________?',
        alternatives: ['River dominated Delta','Tide Dominated Delta','Wave Dominated Delta','None of the above'],
        correct: 'Tide Dominated Delta',
        expo: 'Most important tide dominated deltas of the world include those formed at the mouth of Ganga-Brahmaputra River, Indus River, Mekong River, Irrawaddy river etc.',
    },

    {
        id: 08,
        question: 'India’s largest petrochemical complex is located at:',
        alternatives: ['Gujarat','Maharastra','Rajasthan','Assam'],
        correct: 'Gujarat',
        expo: 'Gujarat is India’s largest petrochemical complex',
    },

    {
        id: 09,
        question: 'India’s first Fast Breeder Reactor (FBR) for commercial nuclear energy generation in Kalpakkam has the following capacity in MWe',
        alternatives: ['200 MWe','220 MWe','440 MWe','500 MWe'],
        correct: '500 MWe',
        expo: 'India’s Prototype Fast Breeder Reactor (PFBR) is a sodium-cooled fast breeder nuclear reactor currently under construction at the Indira Gandhi Centre for Atomic Research in Kalpakkam, Tamil Nadu.',
    },

    {
        id: 10,
        question: 'For which of the following the Kiriburu and Meghahatuburu mines are famous?',
        alternatives: ['Magnesite','Lime Stone','Iron Ore','Silica Sand'],
        correct: 'Iron Ore',
        expo: 'Kiriburu is a town in Jharkhand mainly known for having big Iron-ore Mines KIOM (Kiriburu Iron-Ore Mine) & MIOM (Meghahatuburu Iron-Ore Mine)both governed by Steel Authority of India Limited (SAIL).',
    },

]